Junxiao **Wang**AIGC Researcher | Developer/Engineer Python/PyTorch

% jxiao.wang ♀ github.com/wangjunxiao in linkedin.com/in/junxiao-wang ☐ (+86) 13478902794 ☑ wangjunxiao@live.com ☞ scholar.google.com

i Born Weihai, China, 1991



Several years of experience applying machine learning models *efficiently*, *faithfully*, *securely*, and *privately* in distributed systems. Enjoys contributing to open source and tech communities by sharing knowledge and experience. Interested in designing better problem-solving methods for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools.

Profession & Skills

Programming Python (PyTorch), Golang, Java, C/C++

Machine Learning Quantization, Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning, Federated Learning

CV/NLP/Multimodal Diffusion, GAN, VAE, VIT, CNN, GPT, BERT, GNN, CLIP

PC/Reviewers CVPR25, AISTATS25, IJCAI24, ECCV24, AISTATS24, ICCV23, TC, TMC, TIFS, etc.

Misc Tools Git, LaTex, Linux

</> Projects & Experiences

Mar 2024 Feb 2023

Pre-Trained Models, KAUST, Python (PyTorch)

- > Implementation of Faithful Interpretation with Concept Bottleneck model.
- > Implanting triggerable but invisible *Trojans* in BERT via random encoding perturbation.
- > Slow-Learning Modality Rebalance based on Prototypes implemented with Python.
- > Implementation of *Diffusion Concept Negation* with test-time attention refinement.
- > Publications: KDD23, NeurIPS23, CVPR23, ICLR24.
- > **①**: Modal-Imbalance-PMR, TrojanAttack.

Faithful Interpretation Concept Bottleneck Trojan Modality Rebalance Diffusion

Mar 2023 Mar 2021

Distributed Machine Learning, Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Python (PyTorch)

- > Gradient Protection based on Random Matrix theory implemented with Python.
 - > Knowledge Editing based on TF-IDF and Filter Pruning implemented with NNI.
 - > Implementation of CLIP based *Distributed Framework* with Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning.
 - > Publications: INFOCOM22, IJCAI22, WWW22, WWW23, TMC, Network.
 - → **Ω**: GradDefense, Unlearning, PromptFL.

Gradient Random Matrix TF-IDF Filter Pruning NNI CLIP Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning

Sep 2019

Network Intelligence, QMUL, Python/C/C++

Sep 2018

- > Online *Traffic Recognition* based on 1D-CNN implemented with TensorFlow and Keras.
- > Implementation of adaptive *Sketch Memory Allocation* with Actor-Critic Framework.
- ${\color{blue} > } \ \, \text{Implementation of } \textit{RFID Integrity Authentication} \ \, \text{with protocol design}.$
- > Publications: ICA3PP19, CFI19, SmartIoT19, IoTJ, TMC.
- > **(7)**: TrafficCategorization, HBLSketch, RL_MemoryAllocation.

Traffic Recognition | Sketch | Memory Allocation | Actor-Critic | RFID

Dec 2020 Sep 2016

Network Systems, Dalian University of Technology, Python/Golang/Java/C/C++

- > Implementation of efficient *Software Upgrade* with State-Isolated Modular Management.
- > Implementation of fine-grained *Control Plane Scheduling* with Queue Management.
- > Data Plane Flow Tracing based on Probabilistic Packet Tagging implemented with Python.
- > Publications: SIGCOMM18 Demo, ISJ, TNSM, TNSE, IoTJ, OJCOMS.
- > **Q**: CLICK-UP, FlowTracer, NFVCloud, SDNCloud, SDNDashboard, AgileScheduler.

Software Upgrade Control Plane Scheduling Queue Data Plane Flow Tracing Packet Tagging

Employment

2024-now	Associate Professor, Guangzhou University (GZHU), Guangzhou, China		
2023-2024	Postdoctoral Fellow, King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST), Thuwal, Saudi Arab		
2021-2023	Postdoctoral Fellow, Hong Kong Polytechnic University (PolyU), Hong Kong, China		
2018-2019	Visiting Student Queen Mary University of London (OMUL) London United Kingdom		

Education

0000	DI D : C :	D 1: 11 : 11		V D I: CI :
7(1)7(1	Phillip (amplifar Sciance	a Halian Hnivarcitv	of lachnology/IIIII	l llalian (hina
2020	PhD in Computer Science	z, Dalian Oniversity	OF ICCITIONER (DOT	, Dallan, Cillia

- 2017 MEng in Computer Science, Dalian University of Technology (DUT), Dalian, China
- 2014 BEng in Software Engineering, Dalian Maritime University (DMU), Dalian, China

Publications

- > Liangyu Wang, Jie Ren, Hang Xu, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, David E. Keyes, Di Wang. ZO-Offloading: Fine-Tuning LLMs with 100 Billion Parameters on a Single GPU. The <u>NeurIPS Works</u>hop on Adaptive Foundation Models (AFM) 2024, Vancouver, Canada.
- > Liangyu Wang, Junxiao Wang, Jie Ren, Zihang Xiang, David E. Keyes, Di Wang. FlashDP: Memory-Efficient and High-Throughput DP-SGD Training for Large Language Models. The NeurIPS Workshop on Adaptive Foundation Models (AFM) 2024, Vancouver, Canada.
- > Peiran Dong, Bingjie Wang, Song Guo, Junxiao Wang, Jie Zhang, Zicong Hong. Towards Safe Concept Transfer of Multi-Modal Diffusion via Causal Representation Editing. The Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2024, Vancouver, Canada. (acceptance rate~25.8% [4,043/15,671])
- > Tao Guo, Song Guo, Junxiao Wang. Explore and Cure: Unveiling Sample Effectiveness with Context-Aware Federated Prompt Tuning. IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC) 2024.
- > Jiahuan Pei, Irene Viola, Haochen Huang, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Moonisa Ahsan, Fanghua Ye, Jiang Yiming, Yao Sai, Di Wang, Zhumin Chen, Pengjie Ren, Pablo Cesar. Autonomous Workflow for Multimodal Fine-Grained Training Assistants Towards Mixed Reality. Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL) 2024, Bangkok, Thailand. (acceptance rate∼22.1% [974/4,407])
- > Yizhi Zhou, Junxiao Wang (Corresponding Author), Xiangyu Kong, Shan Wu, Xin Xie, Heng Qi. Exploring Amplified Heterogeneity Arising from Heavy-Tailed Distributions in Federated Learning. IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC) 2024.
- > Liangyu Wang, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Di Wang. Towards Light Adaptation of Large Language Models For Personal Hardware. The ACM MobiSys Workshop on Edge and Mobile Foundation Models (EdgeFM) 2024, Tokyo, Japan.
- > Leijie Wu, Song Guo, Yaohong Ding, Junxiao Wang, Wenchao Xu, Yufeng Zhan, Anne-Marie Kermarrec. Rethinking Personalized Client Collaboration in Federated Learning. IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC) 2024.
- > Songning Lai, Lijie Hu, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Laure Berti-Equille, Di Wang. Faithful Vision-Language Interpretation via Concept Bottleneck Models. International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2024, Vienna, Austria. (acceptance rate~31.0% [2,252/7,262])
- > Peiran Dong, Song Guo, <u>Junxiao Wang</u> (Corresponding Author), Bingjie Wang, Jiewei Zhang, Ziming Liu. Towards Test-Time Refusals via Concept Negation. The Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2023, New Orleans, LA, USA. (acceptance rate~26.1% [3,222/12,343])
- > Tao Guo, Song Guo, Junxiao Wang (Corresponding Author), Xueyang Tang, Wenchao Xu. PromptFL: Let Federated Participants Cooperatively Learn Prompts Instead of Models Federated Learning in Age of Foundation Model. IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC) 2023.
- > Peiran Dong, Song Guo, <u>Junxiao Wang</u> (Corresponding Author). Investigating Trojan Attacks on Pre-trained Language Model-powered Database Middleware. ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD) 2023, Long Beach, CA, USA. (acceptance rate~22.1% [313/1,416])
- > Yunfeng Fan, Wenchao Xu, Haozhao Wang, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Song Guo. PMR: Prototypical Modal Rebalance for Multimodal Learning. IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023, Vancouver, Canada. (acceptance rate~25.8% [2,360/9,155])
- > Tao Guo, Song Guo, Junxiao Wang (Corresponding Author). pFedPrompt: Learning Personalized Prompt for Vision-Language Models in Federated Learning. The ACM Web Conference (WWW) 2023, Austin, Texas, USA. (acceptance rate~19.2% [365/1,900])
- > Leijie Wu, Song Guo, <u>Junxiao Wang</u> (Corresponding Author), Zicong Hong, Jie Zhang, Yaohong Ding. Federated Unlearning: Guarantee the Right of Clients to Forget. IEEE Network 2022.
- > Xin Xie, Xiulong Liu, Junxiao Wang, Song Guo, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li. Efficient Integrity Authentication Scheme for Large-scale RFID Systems. IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC) 2022.
- > Rui Zhang, Song Guo, <u>Junxiao Wang</u> (Corresponding Author), Xin Xie, Dacheng Tao. A Survey on Gradient Inversion: Attacks, Defenses and Future Directions. International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2022, Vienna, Austria. (acceptance rate~14.9% [679/4,535])
- > Junxiao Wang, Song Guo, Xin Xie, Heng Qi. Federated Unlearning via Class-Discriminative Pruning. The ACM Web Conference (WWW) 2022, Online. (acceptance rate~17.7% [323/1,822])
- > Junxiao Wang, Song Guo, Xin Xie, Heng Qi. Protect Privacy from Gradient Leakage Attack in Federated Learning. IEEE International Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM) 2022, Online. (acceptance rate~19.8% [224/1,129])
- > Heng Qi, Junxiao Wang, Wenxin Li, Yuxin Wang, Tie Qiu. A Blockchain-driven IIoT Traffic Classification Service for Edge Computing. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoTJ) 2021.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Wenxin Li, Keqiu Li, Steve Uhlig, Yuxin Wang. Dynamic SDN Control Plane Request Assignment in NFV Datacenters. IEEE Transactions on Network Science and Engineering (TNSE) 2021.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li, Steve Uhlig. Click-UP: Towards the Software Upgrade of Click based Modular Network Function. IEEE Systems Journal (ISJ) 2020.
- > Xinping Xu, Wenxin Li, Heng Qi, Junxiao Wang, Keqiu Li. Latency-Constrained Cost-Minimized Request Allocation for Geodistributed Cloud Services. IEEE Open Journal of the Communications Society (OJCOMS) 2020.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Yang He, Wenxin Li, Keqiu Li. FlowTracer: An Effective Flow Trajectory Detection Solution Based on Probabilistic Packet Tagging in SDN-Enabled Networks. IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management (TNSM) 2019
- > Keyan Zhao, Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Xin Xie, Keqiu Li. HBL-Sketch: A New Three-tier Sketch for Accurate Network Measurement. International Conference on Algorithms and Architectures for Parallel Processing (ICA3PP) 2019, Melbourne, Australia.

- > Wenrui Zhou, Yuan Cao, Heng Qi, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>. An Effective Network Intrusion Detection Framework Based on Learning to Hash. IEEE International Conference on Smart Internet of Things (SmartloT) 2019, Tianjin, China.
- > Wanqian Zhang, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Sheng Chen, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li. A Framework for Resource-aware Online Traffic Classification Using CNN. International Conference on Future Internet Technologies (CFI) 2019, Phuket, Thailand.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li, Xiaobo Zhou. Real-Time Link Fault Detection as a Service for Datacenter Network. Journal of Computer Research and Development 2018.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li, Xiaobo Zhou. PRSFC-loT: A Performance and Resource Aware Orchestration System of Service Function Chaining for Internet of Things. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoTJ) 2018.
- > Junxiao Wang, Yuchen Huang, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li, Steve Uhlig. CLICK-UP: Towards Software Upgrades of Click-driven Stateful Network Element. ACM SIGCOMM Conference 2018 Demo, Budapest, Hungary.